Hello everyone, welcome back to today's our MySQL tutorial series. So today I just
going to learn how to alter table in MySQL, which is an essentially skill for modifying
a structure of your database. Okay, so first of all, I can simply explain for MySQL
alter table statement in the MySQL is to modify the existing table. It allows us to add
to modify the drop down column and now just explore and how it works for some examples. Okay,
so now first of all here, I'll create this statement and just starting for here adding the column
to the table. Okay, so just to go here and first of all here, I can just type the alter table.
So here I can use for the table's name, suppose like the employees. Okay, so the employees
and then go to the next step and here just add the columns from the user phone number. Okay,
so H1A phone underscore this number and here I can use this barcode. Okay, which is great,
completely visible barcode and here insert the size of 20. Okay,
now here define this perfectly and here use the alter table statement to add a new column
for the phone number. Okay, so now just select an execute and as you can see the barcode is now
defined here. So now just remove. Okay, so just completely remove and add for the column. So here
I can select and then again execute now here the employee does not exist. So here not permission
said, okay, so no problem. So just go here first on again here show for here this employee stable.
Okay, so first of all, I can just go for the drop table here inside for the database and also just
go for the sales database and then show for the create table section and here you can see here
no, still for the table of section and here I let for the phone number. Okay, so the phone number
and this is the bar and size here 20. Okay, now here define perfectly and inside all and just
executing and here this comment is completely successful. Okay, so just go for here simply,
I can select for use this open for another new query and first of all, I can just select
from the employees and now just select and not now just your select all and inside here and you
can see here perfectly altered from the number column. Okay, and here perfectly add this column
and next step here, I can create the modify the existing column. Okay, so just go for again here,
just create for all two taping. So here you can employ and now just remember add and here I
can create suppose like the modify column. Okay, so define this modify column and modify
not modify column. So you can choose here write this email column, this is the bar code
for here one which this is the not null. Okay, so you can select this and completely
see the output for here. So now just select and the next code and you can see here the result. Okay,
now here you can see completely see the command is completely successful and now just verify
this comment. So here I can just go for this table inside and just reload now and then go for
inside and choose the database and also choose the sales database and I can go for here the table
and you can see here click for the employee stable and select for the column. So you can see here
this email for here is 100 for in this bar code for the text size. Okay, I hope you completely
understand this. So completely create to accept to statement and next step here, I can create
this is used the dropping a column from the tables of first of all here, I can create this
alter table. So define for the table's name is product. Okay, so now just choose again. So you
can see this product table and now just drop for this and here the price is a stock quantity
and just drop. Okay, so just drop table name is products and 10 here, I can just wait for drop column
name CEO LUM in his column name for stop underscore quantity. Okay, so this one perfect now just
write and select and execute and you can see here correctly syntax now. So I can just try for
an info for this name column. So now again product table from here, try for this column.
So now just execute and there first I can just again select and execute and you can see here
this command and just here I can reload in this another section and into the database inside
the cells and the table and you can select here another table product. Okay, so now just type
you can select inside and execute existing for this. Okay, so here I can just use a product
and another example column. So first of all there I can select and delete now and just wait
select this and you can see perfectly new drop for this column. So second I can define and see here
I hope you perfect understand to the session and you have completely learned this table. So
here I hope you perfect understand the session. So thank you for watching and here completely
you have the overview, the MySQL with the sub program with the practical example. So thank you
for watching and happy coding. Okay,